Register to The David Kraehenbuehl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Biographical Materials, Series VII
  - High School (Box 13, Folder 203)
    Expense Book kept by Kathryn Kraehenbuehl, 1938-1939
    Book of memos kept by Kathryn Kraehenbuehl, 1937-1944
  - High School (Box 13, Folder 204)
    U and I 1939: University High School Yearbook
  - University of Illinois, 1940-1943 (Box 13, Folder 205)
    Awards, invitations, commencement and events programs
  - U. S. Army, 1944-1946 (Box 13, Folder 206)
    Documents, including commission and discharge papers [some photostats]
  - David Kraehenbuehl journal entries, March 12-19, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 207)
  - Wedding announcement, Marie Antoinette Marek to John David Kraehenbuehl, August 9, 1947 (Box 13, Folder 207)
  - Yale University (Box 13, Folder 208)
    Diplomas: BMus. 1948, MMus. 1949
    Commencement program, 1949
  - Schola Cantorum Basiliensis (Box 13, Folder 209)
    List of classes taken, 1950
  - Yale School of Music News-Letter, New Series, No. 11 July, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 209)
  - Yale School of Music Alumni Association (Box 17, Folder 238)
    Certificate of Merit, October 8, 1983
  - Typescript biographies (Box 13, Folder 209)
    [2 versions: 2 pp., 1 p.]
  - Typescript obituary (Box 13, Folder 210)
  - Obituary from The New York Times (Box 13, Folder 210)
    (photocopy)
  - Typescript list of Kraehenbuehl children and grandchildren (Box 13, Folder 210)
  - Presidential memorial citation, signed William Jefferson Clinton (Box 13, Folder 210)
- Miscellaneous Materials, Series VIII
  - Materials relating to family (Box 13, Folder 211)
    - Class Yell, Motto
    - Commencement invitation, Knoxville High School, 1918
    - Commencement program from the University of Tennessee, June 7, 1922
    - Die Kolonie Bernstadt in Laurel County, Kentucky, 1940
    - PreSchool Soliloquy by Dorothy Ashby Pownall, Nov. 5, 1932
    - Program for play Cupid at Vassar, May 26, 1913
  - Diaries and date books kept by Kathryn Kraehenbuehl
    - 1922, 1938, 1939, 1940 (Box 13, Folder 212)
    - 1941/45, 1942, 1946/50 (Box 14, Folder 213)
    - 1951/55, 1956/60, 1961/65 (Box 14, Folder 214)
    - 1966/70, 1971/75, 1976/80 (Box 14, Folder 215)
    - 1981/82 (Box 14, Folder 216)
  - Ticket stubs (2), New Haven Symphony, Outdoor "Pops" Concert, June 28, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 217)
  - Poster for Princeton Pro Musica performance, March 23, 1986 premiere of Drumfire (Box 18)
  - Book of reminiscences, Keyboard Arts Association Chicago, July 10, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 218)
  - University High School 50th Class Reunion, October 22, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 218)
    News clipping
    Reprint of pages from U and I 1939 yearbook, with greetings from class
  - Invitation to concert of La Crosse Philharmonic and La Crosse Youth Symphony, November 25, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 218)
  - Happy Birthday: September 15 (New York: Natalis Press, c.1993) (Box 15, Folder 218)
    Inscribed: Happy Birthday, Honey. Love, Me.
  - Bush Artist Fellowships application, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 218)
    Photocopy (8 p.)
  - U. S. flag from funeral, January 7, 1997 (Box 18)
  - Menu from the Johnny-Cake Inn, Ivoryton, CT, with eight signatures on cover, including Blanche Porto and Richard Owens (Box 15, Folder 219)
  - Our Director (To a Wonderful Director) by a second bass (Box 15, Folder 219)
    Typescript poem with manuscript dynamic markings in ink
    Written by a member of the New Haven Chorale
  - List of piano works with timings, headed Ultimate II Program (Box 15, Folder 219)
    Photocopy (2 p.)
  - Music of David Kraehenbuehl in the Frank Italiano Music Library (Box 15, Folder 219)
    Typescript, 2 p.
  - A Big Book Fair, 5 p. (Box 18, Folder 239)
    Text and drawings by first-grade students who saw
    A Very Special House, music by David Kraehenbuehl
  - The Amphibious Eighth. Prepared and edited by the 8th Army Historical Section. Printed by the AG Printing Plant. (Box 15, Folder 220)
    Some pages marked and annotated.
  - Documents relating to The New School for Music Study and the National Keyboard Arts Associates (Box 15, Folder 222)
    - The New School for Music Study
      reprinted from The Piano Teacher, September-October 1960
      4 pp.
    - A Prospectus for the National Piano Arts Associates
      typescript, 4 pp.
    - Teaching Techniques '75 [brochure]
  - Documents relating to the J. S. Paluch Co. (Box 15, Folder 223)
    - Music development program: new songs for celebration. -- Chicago: J. S. Paluch Co., c.1979., 22 cm.; 25 p.
      Unaccompanied melodies with text and chord symbols.
      Some works may be by David Kraehenbuehl.
    - Compositions and arrangements by David Kraehenbuehl
      typescript, 1 p.
    - Memo from Rita Cavallaro to WLP Management, June 27, 1996
      re: Titles - David Kraehenbuehl, 2 p.
    - List of David Kraehenbuehl harmonizations in the Paluch Organ Accompaniment Book
    - Music Development Program Purchases, 1 p.
    - Some Findings of Recent Monthly Missalette Music Survey, 1 p.
- Sound Recordings, Series IX
  Sound recordings have been transferred to the Historical Sound Recordings Collection in the Music Library. For further information about archival recordings relating to David Kraehenbuehl, please contact the Curator of Historical Sound Recordings.
- Additions, Series X
  Scope and Contents
  Added here are materials that arrived after the processing of the Kraehenbuehl Papers was completed. They have been added to the Papers because of their provenance or their relationship to other materials in the collection.
  This series may be updated from time to time. The most current inventory of Additions to the Kraehenbuehl Papers is kept on file in the Music Library Office.
  - [Piano music. Selections. Rev. ed.] The collected works for solo piano / David Kraehenbuehl; edited by Martha Braden. Revised ed. New York: Martha Braden, c.1999 by Martha Braden, revised ed. June 2000., 1 score (130 p.); 29 cm. (Box 15, Folder 240)
    Contents: Diptych. -- Toccate per Cembalo. -- A Formal Triad. -- Toccata sopra B-A-C-H. -- Random Walks. -- Looking Back: Twelve Images from My Past.
  - The ultimate music box / Christopher U. Light; David Kraehenbuehl. -- Ocean City, NJ: Musical Heritage Society, 1988-91. (Box 15, Folder 240)
    2 sound discs; digital stereo; 4 3/4 in.
    "A computerized re-creation of pieces for lost mechanical instruments."
    Gift of Christopher Light.
    Cataloged separately in the recordings collections of the Music Library.